Résumé for Ibrahim Dauda

Resident Address - 2, L Street, Babangida, FHA, Lugbe, Airport Road, Abuja.

 Mobile
 - +234 9068190646

 Email
 - ibrolive@gmail.com

LinkedIn – https://ng.linkedin.com/in/ibrahimdauda

Github – https://github.com/ibrolive

Nationality – Nigerian Experience – ~15 years Travel/Relocate? – Yes

Remote Work? - Yes



Introduction

I am a full-stack software engineer with DevOps CI/CD, Quality Assurance automation and applications support experience. I write front and back-end code in Javascript, C#/ASP.NET and SQL databases. I often deploy applications to Microsoft Azure/AWS. I also perform application testing manually and using automated tools including Katalon Studio and Selenium.

Work Experience

MOST RECENT EXPERIENCE

Position: Software Engineering Team Lead

I engage in full-time software development projects using Javascript and .NET technology stack. I'm also responsible for managing the DevOps CI/CD cycle on Azure, in addition to overseeing functional testing and quality assurance automation (with ZapTest, Selenium and Katalon Studio). Some of my more recent engagements include:

- Date: March 2017 - Date

Company: Techspecialist Consulting Limited

Description: Software Engineer with DevOps and QA experience.

I've held several roles at Techspecialist. I started out as a freelance developer contracted by Techspecialist to build a Housing Market Information Portal (HMIP) for the Nigeria Mortgage Refinance Company (NMRC) [see link http://hmip.nmrc.com.ng]. After that, Techspecialist decided to setup an in-house software development team, and I was hired to build that team, so I became the software team lead for Techspecialist, and with my team we built another product, an Appraisal Management System (AMS), for our satisfied customer, NMRC. My team and I also built other fabulous solutions that we're super proud of. We're currently building ProcureEase, a procurement solution, with VueJS frontend, NodeJS backend and MySQL database. Over the years, as a result of the constantly evolving needs of our dynamic team, I've transitioned from Lead Developer, to Lead Backend Developer, to Lead DevOps, Quality Assurance and Testing.

- Date: December 2016 - February 2017

Company: Nasarawa State University, Keffi (NSUK) School of Post Graduate Studies (SPGS), Nasarawa, Nigeria **Description:** AFIS Biometric User Data Capture System was customized in Safari and deployed for the post graduate school in Keffi. On this project, I used bootstrap frontend, MVC.NET (C#) backend and Microsoft SQL Server database.

- Date: August 2016 - November 2016

Company: Nigeria Mortgage Refinance Company (NMRC) / Techspecialist, Abuja, Nigeria **Description:** I developed a Housing Market Information Portal (HMIP) which collates housing market data and generates business intelligence charts for decision making. On this project I used vanilla Javascript, MVC.NET (C#) backend, and Microsoft SQL Server database.

OTHER PAST EXPERIENCE

Position: Web Developer

Employer: Onepay-Global, Abuja, Nigeria

Date: April 2014 - May 2015

Description:

Onepay-Global was an electronic transaction switching and payment processing company. My responsibilities included developing software for the payment gateway and providing levels 2 and 3 application support for the company's clients. I converted my full time contract to part time to enable me more flexible timings. Onepay-Global has since been rebranded to SaanaPay [see link http://saanapay.com/]

Position: Chief Technical Officer - Operations, Development & Support

Employer: IGMB Solutions, Kaduna, Nigeria

Date: August 2013 - March 2014

Description:

IGMB Solutions is an online-based software and web development, and hosting company.

I started the company with 3 friends back in 2008, and since then our team has focused on website design, desktop and mobile application development, and deployment of business applications (including School/Campus Management Systems using Fedena and BlackBoard, eLearning Management Systems, and HRM Systems amongst others).

At IGMB Solutions, I went from marketing to consulting to implementation. I gained a lot of experience building the new start up company. IGMB Solutions has since launched its own hosting solution: http://www.igmbhost.com.

Position: L2 Applications Support Engineer

Employer: Tech Mahindra, Accra, Ghana

Date: August 2012 - June 2013

Description:

Tech Mahindra represents the new connected world, offering innovative and customer-centric IT services and solutions integrating technology with business. It is a global multinational provider of information technology, networking technology solutions and Business Process Outsourcing to the telecommunications industry.

At Tech Mahindra, I was part of a team that maintained telecom applications for Tigo (a telecom operator) across six African countries (including Ghana, Senegal, Rwanda, Democratic Republic of Congo, Tanzania, and Chad). Our activities included the use, maintenance, administration and upgrade of about 150 telecom applications ranging from mediation, VAS, IN, Roaming to DWH and BI.

I had one of the most positively challenging, fast-paced and dynamic experiences working in Tech Mahindra. The team was excellent and highly professional, but I had to leave my position at Tech Mahindra. I was ready to settle down finally, so I moved back to Nigeria, attended a 1-year (compulsory) paramilitary service, and also got married.

Position: Web Developer

Employer: Explainer DC, Accra, Ghana (now Cobalt Partners)

Date: January 2011 - June 2012

Description:

Explainer DC is a Web development company in Ghana helping companies leverage on the Internet as a medium of communication. We also offered web hosting and ISP internet services. Over a decade, it developed and managed more than 300 websites and online assets for Corporates, Multinationals, SMEs and Individuals in Ghana and offshore.

At Explainer DC, I worked alongside a team of Project Managers, Senior and Junior Developers, Graphics Designers, Web Designers, and Content Editors. I developed web sites and applications primarily with ASP.NET using Visual Studio, and SQL Server and also using the Kentico CMS. My team also deployed, hosted and maintained websites. Sites developed include: the official Vodafone Ghana website, MCNet Mozambique – a port management application for Mozambique; a database for fertilizer in Africa; among others. Explainer DC was acquired by Cobalt Partners in 2015.

I had one of the best experiences and working conditions at Explainer DC, made friends in the Explainer DC "family", but sadly I left my position to gain experience in the telecom industry, providing application support, and to settle down and raise a family.

Position: Software/Web Development

Employer: SOI Consulting Ltd, Kaduna, Nigeria

Date: February 2009 - February 2010

Description:

SOI Consulting is an indigenous IT Solutions and Service Provider with the goal of being the Foremost IT Solution and Service Provider in Africa by Leveraging Solutions, Expertise and Global Alliances with IT vendors across the globe to create a powerful and unique brand in the field of IT consulting.

At SOI Consulting, I was a full time Web designer and Developer. I also consulted on Oracle ECM products, while training students, partners, users, and new recruits on various software related courses.

I left my position at SOI Consulting to relocate to Accra, Ghana to gain a Bachelor's degree in Information Technology while gaining more experience in wider range of industries.

Position: Trainer

Employer: National Institute of Information Technology, NIIT, Kaduna & Zaria, Nigeria

Date: September 2007 - February 2009

Description:

National Institute for Information Technology (NIIT) is a leading global talent development multinational corporation that offers learning management and training delivery solutions to corporations, institutions and individuals.

At NIIT, I taught students Information Technology courses ranging from Software and Web Development, to Database Administration using Sun Java, Microsoft .NET and SQL Server.

I left my teaching job at NIIT to practice what I had been teaching and gain field experience.

Trainings & Certifications

Trainings

- Quality Assurance Testing & Automation with Selenium and Katalon Studio June 2019
- Business Analysis June 2019
- Azure DevOps CI / CD June 2019
- Certified Ethical Hacking (CEH7) January 2016
- Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) November 2015
- Project Management Professional (PMP) October 2015
- SQL Server Administration May 2015

Certifications

- Microsoft Certified Professional October 2016 (ID: 13499793)
- Microsoft Certified Web Developer October 2016 (ID: 13499793)

Education

Software Engineering bootcamp:

Training in remote work for full stack web development — May 2019 – December 2019 From: Microverse (on-going)

Degree:

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology — August 2010 – June 2012 From: University of Education, Winneba, Ghana

Diploma:

Professional Diploma in Software Engineering — April 2004 – December 2007 From: National Institute of Information Technology (NIIT), Kaduna, Nigeria

High School:

SSCE/WASSCE — January 1998 – February 2004 From: Clara Secondary School, Kaduna, Nigeria

Interests

